Liverpool, UK | linkedin.com/benpowelldev/

Technical Skills

Languages: C++ (1 Year) C# (1 Year) Python (3 Years)

Software Experience: Windows 10, Visual Studio 2013–2019, 3ds Max, Unreal Engine, Photoshop, Perforce

Gameplay Programming : Implementation of both gameplay and logic in C++, including VR, Enemy Spawning, and game asset functionality. Using Unreal Blueprints and C++.

Other: Have experience working within teams of up to 8, with both artists and programmers, on university projects, taking roles such as: a gameplay programmer, game designer and music designer.

Previous Project Experience

VR Assassin Game | 2019 - Present

Role: Solo Game Developer

Languages: C++ and Unreal Blueprints

Description : This is a VR Assassins Creed Simulator, in which you take on the Hidden Blade, and sneak your way through a well-guarded facility in order to assassinate your target. With both C++ and Blueprints in use, I implemented the hidden blade as well as climb mechanics to make getting to the target more engaging.

'Untitled Game' | 2019

Role : Gameplay Programmer (Team of 6) **Languages :** Unreal Engine Blueprints

Description : This was a small 2d game I worked on just at the beginning my university studies, in which the player was sent on a task to cause as much havoc as possible by destroying buildings, harassing bystanders and being a general pain. All completed with Unreal Blueprints and C++.

Work Experience

Aria PC | Systems Builder Internship | 2016-2017

Description : I worked as an intern building computer systems with Aria PC in Manchester. I was working alongside CyberPower PC, one of the countries biggest companies for custom systems within the UK. I Built both high-end and low-end systems with both consumer and enterprise hardware.

Education

LIVERPOOL JOHN MOORES UNIVERSITY | COMPUTER GAMES DEVELOPMENT | GRADUATING 2024 Master of Computing in Computer Games Development, on course to graduate with at least a 2:1

Miscellaneous

Favorite Games: The Legend of Zelda Franchise, Pavlov VR, Assassins Creed II, Geometry Wars, Pistol Whip VR, VTOL VR, PokerStars VR.